Guide to the William Upcott, Collection of Autograph Letters
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
[Collection of autograph letters of various English peers, statesmen, antiquaries, etc.]
1701-1900
OSBORN C232
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.13
(1 volume)
MS.
Upcott, William, 1779-1845
Immediate Source of Acquisition
For provenance information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The following finding aid is a complete inventory of the contents of Osborn c232. This list was reformatted from previously existing cataloging.
Antiquarians -- Great Britain; Collectors and collecting -- Great Britain; Great Britain -- Social life and customs -- 18th century; Great Britain -- Social life and customs -- 19th century; Correspondence; George, King of Great Britain, IV, 1762-1830; Monteagle, Thomas Spring Rice, 1st baron, 1790-1866; Pembroke, Henry Herbert, Earl of, 1734-1794; Richmond, Charles Gordon-Lennox, Duke of, 1791-1860; Smith, John Thomas, 1766-1833; Upcott, William, 1779-1845
- Osborn c232
  - ANONYMOUS
    - ALS to William Upcott (1779-1845), 1827 Sep 15
      Scope and Contents
      [Portsmouth]
      1 p.; 23 x 18 cm.
      232/49
  - BADEN, DOWAGER DUCHESS OF
    - Invitation to receive Mr. Farr [?Revd Thomas Farr], 1841 2 Sep
      Baden
      1 p.; 22 x 14 cm.
      A note at the bottom of the
      invitation, in the hand of the
      Duchess's chamberlain, thanks Mr.
      Farr for the packet which he
      previously sent.
      232/57
  - GEORGE IV, KING OF GT. BRIT., 1762-1830
    - Letter to James Heath (1757-1834), 1809 May 11
      n.p.
      1 p.; 18 x 12 cm.
      232/8
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - Envelope Addressed to Revd Thos Farr, 1841 Mar 23
      Beccles
      1 p.; 19 x 16 cm.
      Postal Cancellations.
      232/12
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - Envelope Addressed to: Monsieur Mons. Heris, Rue Royale N. 112 a Bruxelles., n.d.
      1 p.;20 x 24 cm.
      232/39
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - Envelope Addressed to D. W. Turner, 1842 Nov 28
      Yarmouth- Norfolk
      1 p.; 7 x 12 cm.
      Postal cancellations.
      232/48
  - MONTEAGLE, THOMAS SPRING-RICE, 1ST BARON, 1790-1866
    - ALS to an unidentified recipient, 1819 Dec 5
      Nenagh
      Will clear off the debt of the late
      Sir Vere Hunt.
      232/22
  - NEAL, H.
    - ALS to Dawson Turner, 1845 May 11
      Worlingham
      1 p.; 23 x 28 cm.
      Sale of a property; accompanied by a
      printed version of "Testimonials"
      concerning W.W. Simpson.
      232/52-3
  - PATRICK, F. C.
    - ALS to Mary (Palgrave) Turner, 1822 Aug 24
      Portman Street
      2 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      Mary Palgrave became Mrs. Dawson
      Turner.
      232/7
  - PATTEN, WILLIAM
    - ALS to Nicolas Mori (1797-1839), 1837 Aug 7
      Winchester
      1 p.; 24 x 19 cm.
      With title page of Patten's
      "Congregational Melodies".
      232/6
  - PEMBROKE, HENRY HERBERT, 10TH EARL OF, 1734-1794
    - ALS to Sir George Savile, 8th bart., (1726-1784), 1766 Sep 8
      Wilton House
      On releasing dragoons of his
      regiment.
      232/13
  - PENRICE, THOMAS
    - 2 ALS to Mr. Dulau, bookseller, 1808-12
      1808 Aug 12 and 1812 Jul 21
      Yarmouth and Narford
      2 p.; 24 x 18 cm.
      232/14-15
  - PERKIN, BACON & PATCH
    - ALS to Gurney, Turner & Co., 1845
      1845 Jun 21 and May 9, London
      3 p.; 25 x 20 cm.
      On improved methods of printing
      banknotes and documents.
      232/3-4
  - PEYTON, SIR THOMAS
    - ALS to Sir Thomas Hare, 4th bart. (ca. 1688-1760), 1748 Nov 19
      Emneth
      2 p.; 20 x 16 cm.
      Declines further participation.
      232/5
  - REYNOLDS, WILLIAM, 1758-1803
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, [no year]
      [no year] May 30
      1 p.; 22 x 18 cm.
      232/21
  - RIBBANS, F. B.
    - ALS to the Committee of the Yarmouth Proprietary Grammar School, 1843 Nov 27
      [Edgbaston]
      1 p.; 23 x 18
      232/23
  - RICHMOND, CHARLES GORDON-LENNOX, 5TH DUKE OF, 1791-1860
    - 2 ALS to Thomas William Anson, 1st earl of Lichfield (1795-1854), 1835-37
      1835 Nov 15 and 1837 Feb 6, Goodwood
      7 p.; various sizes
      232/19-20
  - RIGBY, EDWARD, 1804-1860
    - ALS to Dawson Turner (1775-1858), 1834 Feb 6
      44 Parliament Street
      1 p.; 25 x 20 cm.
      S. Gurney is attending his midwifery
      lectures.
      232/2
  - RIVAROL, ANTOINE DE, COUNT, 1753-1801
    - AL (in French) to an unnamed recipient, [1826 or later]
      1 p.; 20 x 16 cm.
      States that the Count has an
      unedited letter of Burke - "On the
      French Revolution".
      232/18
  - RIVINGTON, JOHN, 1720-1792
    - Account (receipted and signed) with Society for Promoting Christian Knowledge, 1783 Apr 7
      [London]
      232/16
  - RIVINGTON, JOHN, 1720-1792
    - ALS to Cadell & Davies, publishers, [no year]
      [no year] Sep 7
      1 p.; 17 x 23 cm.
      232/17
  - SCARSDALE, NATHANIEL CURZON, 2ND BARON, 1751-1837
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, [1806]
      [Derby]
      1 p.; 12 x 19 cm.
      Mounted with an envelope addressed
      to Herries, Farquhar & Co.,
      dated 1817.
      232/1
  - SCHWABE, DR.
    - AL to Charles Frederick Partington (?d. 1857), 1830 Feb 20
      Stamford Hill
      Wants to buy patent feet warmer.
      232/56
  - SEAFORTH, FRANCIS MACKENZIE HUMBERSTON, 1ST BARON, 1754-1815
    - AL to James Christie, 1730-1803, 1799 Jul 22
      Hereford Street
      Attaches inventory requested.
      232/64
  - SEAFORTH, FRANCIS MACKENZIE HUMBERSTON, BARON, 1754-1815
    - AL to George Chalmers (1742-1825), [1799?]
      Princes Street
      232/67
  - SEFTON, WILLIAM PHILIP MOLYNEUX, 2ND EARL OF, 1772-1838
    - ALS to James Christie (1730-1803), [1801 Oct 26]
      Quorn
      3 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      Sale of a house.
      232/68
  - SEWELL, WILLIAM, 1780-1853
    - ALS to Mr. Stephenson, 1813 Dec 29
      Veterinary College
      2 p.; 24 x 19 cm.
      232/69
  - SEYMOUR, LORD HUGH, 1759-1801
    - ALS to General Bentham, 1794
      Admiralty
      232/70
  - SHARP, J. B.
    - ALS to William Upcott (1779-1845), 1822 Jun 26
      21 Arundell Street
      2 p.; 25 x 20 cm.
      Wishes a ticket to the Library for Mr. Gillow.
      232/71
  - SHARPE, W.
    - ALS to John Stevens Henslow, (1796-1861), 1842 Sep 23
      Cambridge
      1 p.; 20 x 13 cm.
      Published about 150 years ago by Mr.
      Gouge of Christ College; Sales letter
      per copy, title not mentioned.
      232/72
  - SHEFFIELD, CHARLES
    - ALS to Joseph Sharpe, 1762 Jul 14
      1 p.; 19 x 20 cm.
      232/62
  - SHEFFIELD, JOHN BAKER HOLROYD, 1ST EARL OF, 1735-1821
    - ALS to John Pinkerton (1758-1826), 1797 Feb 28
      Dublin
      1 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      232/63
  - SHEPHERD, GEORGE SIDNEY, D. 1858
    - 2 ALS and 1 AL to William Upcott, (1779-1845), 1843 Mar 5
      Exmouth Street
      3 p.; 23 x 18 cm.
      Requests advance payment on drawings
      etc. in hand.
      232/59-61
  - SHIPLEY, WILLIAM DAVIES, 1745-1826
    - ALS to Thackeray & Lloyd, 1793 Sep 19
      [St. Asaph]
      Will pay by Christmas.
      232/58
  - SIDMOUTH, HENRY ADDINGTON, 1ST VISCOUNT, 1757-1844
    - ALS to W. Firth, 1817 May 3
      Whitehall
      Thanks for a publication.
      232/55
  - SIMEON, CHARLES, 1759-1836
    - AL to Professor John Stevens Henslow, (1796-1861), 1835 May 19
      Will not be an annual contributor.
      232/54
  - SIMS, RICHARD
    - Printed prospectus for "An Index to the Pedigrees and Arms contained in the Heralds' Visitations, and other Genealogical Manuscripts in the British Museum" with MS annotations by Sims
      1 p.; 22 x 13 cm.
      232/51
  - SINCLAIR, SIR JOHN, BART., 1754-1835
    - AL to John Pinkerton (1758-1826), 1794 Jun
      Makes an appointment.
      232/50
  - SMART, BENJAMIN HUMPHREY, 1786-1872
    - ALS to William Upcott (1779-1845), [1828] Dec 17
      55 Connaught Terrace
      On the date of his lectures.
      232/44
  - SMART, BENJAMIN HUMPHREY, 1786-1872
    - ALS to William Upcott (1779-1845), 1828 Feb 19
      232/47
  - SMITH, ANKER, 1759-1819
    - LS to John Boydell ( 1719-1804), 1793 Sep 25
      Chelsea
      1 p.; 19 x 14 cm.
      Has sent Mr. Brown's plate; requests
      20 Gns.
      232/46
  - SMITH, CULLING EARDLEY
    - ALS to [R.L. Torre], [1830] 5 Sep
      Brighton
      Asks for a subscription to
      translations of the Oxford and
      Cambridge Prize Poems.
      232/45
  - SMITH, J. J.
    - ALS to John Stevens Henslow, 1796-1861, 1837 Oct
      Would include Botanical Museum and
      Gardens.
      232/73
  - SMITH, JOHN
    - ALS to "Jeffrey", 1819 Feb 16
      Request for copies of recently
      published or written materials.
      232/40
  - SMITH, JOHN
    - ALS to unnamed recipient, 1838 Jan 27
      Edinburgh
      Discusses improvements to portrait
      of which the author is possibly
      either the artist or the engraver.
      232/41
  - SMITH, JOHN
    - ALS to Thomas Frognall Dibdin (1776-1841), [no year]
      [no year] Jul 11
      "The Stirrup Cup" is almost
      finished.
      232/42
  - SMITH, JOHN
    - AL to John Lindley (1799-1865), 1845 Mar 4
      Royal Botanic Garden Kew
      1 p.; 21 x 15 cm.
      Discusses flowers in Gardens.
      232/43
  - SMITH, JOHN THOMAS, 1766-1833
    - 2 ALS to William Upcott (1779-1845), 1824-1826
      1824 Mar 25 and 1826 Nov 1
      British Museum
      4 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      232/37-38
  - SMITH, WILLIAM JAMES
    - ALS to William Upcott (1779-1845), 1831 Jan 21
      Stowe
      Discusses a topographical catalogue
      of Upcott's library by Charles
      O'Conor (1710-1791).
      232/34
  - SMITH, WILLIAM JAMES
    - ALS to William Upcott (1779-1845), [no year]
      [no year] Sep 6
      Hopes that Upcott can sell his
      collection.
      232/35
  - SMITH, WILLIAM
    - ALS to Dawson Turner, 1829 Nov 12
      Lisle Street
      Discusses the sale of some prints.
      232/36
  - SOCIETY OF ANTIQUARIES OF SCOTLAND
    - Receipt (printed) to Charles Roach Smith (1807-1890), 1850 May 23
      1 p.; 26 x 20 cm.
      Acknowledging donation of
      "Collectanea Antiqua", vol II,
      part II.
      232/10
  - SOMERS, CAROLINE HARRIET (YORKE), COUNTESS OF, 1795-1873
    - AL to Mr. Rodwell, bookseller, 1830 Nov 17
      Reigate
      232/30
  - SOMERS, JOHN SOMERS-COCKS, 2ND EARL OF, 1788-1852
    - 2 AL to Mr Rodwell, bookseller, 1830 Nov
      1830 Nov 17, 1830 Nov 30
      2 p.; 23 x 18 cm.
      232/31-32
  - SOMERSET, LORD CHARLES HENRY, 1767-1831
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, 1799 Sep 11
      Weymouth
      1 p.; 20 x 19 cm.
      Returning list of the Harmonic
      Society.
      232/28
  - SOMERSET, EDWARD ADOLPHUS SEYMOUR, DUKE OF, 1775-1855
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, 1837 Dec 4
      Park Lane
      232/29
  - SOPWITH, THOMAS, 1803-1879
    - ALS to James Scott Bowerbank (1797-1877), 1845 Dec 1
      Allenheads
      Mr. Robert Stephenson (1803-1859)
      wishes to see Sopwith's new
      microscope.
      232/25
  - SOUTHERN, HENRY, 1799-1853
    - AL to Harriet (Wilde) Valpy (d. 1864), [1824 May]
      Sergeant's Inn
      Invitation declined.
      232/27
  - STEPHEN, JAMES, 1758-1832
    - ALS to Thomas M. Coombes, n.d.
      Kensington Gore
      He cannot attend a meeting.
      232/24
  - STEVENSON, WILLIAM, 1772-1829
    - ALS to William Upcott (1779-1845), 1827 Jan 9
      Treasury
      232/26
  - STEWART, DUNCAN
    - LS to G. Turner, 1845 Aug [2]7
      Calcutta
      Sends smallpox vaccine.
      232/33
  - STOWELL, WILLIAM SCOTT, 1ST BARON, 1745-1836
    - AL to George Chalmers (1742-1825), 1804 Oct 9
      1 p.; 20 x 14 cm.
      Thanks for transmission of a packet
      from Mr. Dyer.
      232/65
  - STOWELL, WILLIAM SCOTT, 1ST BARON, 1745-1836
    - ALS to George Chalmers (1742-1825), 1805 Aug 21
      Reading
      232/66
  - TWISS, WILLIAM, 1745-1827
    - ALS to Sir Samuel Bentham (1757-1831), 1811 May 9
      Chislehurst
      The author is moving to Yorkshire.
      232/11
  - VALPY, ABRAHAM JOHN, 1787-1854
    - LS to an unnamed recipient, 1818 Mar 31
      Tooke's Court
      232/9